<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet href="/pretty-feed-v3.xsl" type="text/xsl"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>skoomaDen</title><description>Welcome to the Skooma Den !</description><link>https://skoomaden.me/</link><item><title>New Teaset, Tray, and an Unpleasant Surprise :/</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/new_teaset/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/new_teaset/</guid><description>I&apos;ve been experimenting with new sources for my teaware. Although it&apos;s not the most elegant option, one of the more affordable sources I decided to try was AliExpress.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;New Teaset, Tray, and an Unpleasant Surprise :/&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello Everyone,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was the day I&apos;ve been eagerly anticipating, as I&apos;ve been experimenting with new sources for my teaware. Although it&apos;s not the most elegant option, one of the more affordable sources I decided to try was AliExpress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s review what I received, comparing my expectations with the actual products:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/F3DVtNN/IMG-8233.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG-8233&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&apos;ll start with the &quot;360 degree gaiwan&quot; or whatever that means. It&apos;s supposedly a gaiwan that you can rotate for easier steeping, featuring a small filter at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expected:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/hy973Wp/Screenshot-2024-04-28-000311.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot-2024-04-28-000311&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And what I got:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/mTY9Yqp/IMG-8229.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG-8229&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only were the cups incredibly small, but they were also of very poor quality... and the gaiwan itself arrived broken...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is this &quot;ceramic&quot; tea tray:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expected:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/bzcyCNQ/Screenshot-2024-04-28-000946.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot-2024-04-28-000946&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I received was this:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brass, incredibly heavy but acceptable quality tea tray. Unfortunately, it doesn&apos;t have a nozzle and doesn&apos;t resemble the photo in the description. :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/BLJ2cCY/IMG-8231.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG-8231&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we have this snail tea pet:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expected:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/VxVpTk4/Screenshot-2024-04-28-001611.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot-2024-04-28-001611&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And I basically received the same, but broken :/&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s adorable, though!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/GcFRkDx/IMG-8234.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG-8234&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And another 360 degree gaiwan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I ordered:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/PDH6w4m/Screenshot-2024-04-28-001950.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot-2024-04-28-001950&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And what I got:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/H7B37wY/IMG-8238.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG-8238&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I only received the gaiwan. I was supposed to get a set with it, but honestly, I&apos;m glad they protected it very well during shipping, and at least this one didn&apos;t break. Either way, the cups would&apos;ve been too small, haha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also treated myself to this teaset from Touthé in Lausanne, a teashop that sells a lot of Palais des Thés stuff. They sold the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expected:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.honoriscausa.fr/8644-large_default/tasse-gaiwan-dragon-bleu-porcelaine-fine.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tasse gaïwan dragon bleu, porcelaine fine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And here it is on my table:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/cF2pCdR/IMG-8240.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMG-8240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks and feels quite nice, definitely the most high-quality teaware out of all the ones I&apos;ve presented today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh well, that was all for today!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you guys! :0&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Tea Review</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>Toaru, or the Crossmedia Paradox.</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/toaru_storytelling/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/toaru_storytelling/</guid><description>Toaru&apos;s journey through the labyrinth of crossmedia and what it means for the future of storytelling.</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;import { YouTube } from &quot;astro-embed&quot;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Toaru, or the Crossmedia Paradox&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although you might not frequently encounter the term &quot;crossmedia&quot; in the English-speaking Internet, it represents the aspiration of nearly every modern franchise within the Francophonie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Numerous failed projects testify to this ambition, such as the French web-series &lt;a href=&quot;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noob_%28web-s%C3%A9rie%29&quot;&gt;Noob&lt;/a&gt; with its attempt to penetrate the gaming scene through a crowd-funded game, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wakfu&quot;&gt;Ankama&apos;s Wakfu&lt;/a&gt;, which continually tries to expand beyond its animated series roots into manga, games, and music. Moreover, I would argue that David Cage&apos;s work on QTE-style games exemplifies crossmedia, attempting to bridge the gap between gaming and movies, albeit superficially.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://jolstatic.fr/www/captures/92/5/69675.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ankama - Wakfu TCG au Monde Du Jeu - Wakfu&quot; /&gt;
Credit: Wakfu (Ankama)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some, these attempts were mildly successful. However, for most, it appears almost impossible for a franchise, even one with a devoted fanbase, to transition its audience to a new medium, regardless of the grandeur of the &lt;em&gt;adaptation&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crux of the issue may lie in the very concept of &quot;adaptation.&quot; The value of a brand name is often misunderstood—it transcends mere recognizability to include familiarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adapting a franchise to a new medium requires significant changes; it must embrace its conventions and fully understand them. This alone creates a daunting, immutable barrier—something &lt;em&gt;unfamiliar&lt;/em&gt;. Even within related domains, such as animation and live-action movies, adaptations frequently face criticism for this unfamiliarity, causing disruption within fandoms (e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Last_Airbender_%28film%29&quot;&gt;The Last Airbender&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a benchmark for our exploration, we will examine a prime example of the cross-media journey, illustrating how, more often than not, &lt;em&gt;it fails in ways that are seemingly unavoidable.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Brief Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Toaru franchise consists of not one, not three, but two principal media forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/k8nb3KL/306933335-399495939049163-8008463402308418097-n.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://toarumajutsunoindex.fandom.com/wiki/Toaru_Majutsu_to_Kagaku_no_Ensemble&quot;&gt;Toaru Majutsu to Kagaku no Ensemble&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt;, both chronologically and in terms of lore, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Certain_Magical_Index&quot;&gt;A Certain Magical Index&lt;/a&gt;, or (とある魔術の禁書目録) for those who might understand Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The series, a collection of light novels written by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kazuma_Kamachi&quot;&gt;Kazuma Kamachi&lt;/a&gt; and illustrated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kiyotaka_Haimura&quot;&gt;Kiyotaka Haimura&lt;/a&gt;, brilliantly crafts a complex and coherent world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.redd.it/7403etrhgfc51.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Light Novel collection so far, waiting for SS volumes to complete OT. :  r/toarumajutsunoindex&quot; /&gt;
Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/RobotiSC&quot;&gt;RobotiSC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toaru&apos;s universe is defined by the dichotomy between magic and science. The novels center on Kamijo Toma, a high school student residing in Academy City, the most scientifically advanced city in the series&apos; universe. Unlike many students there, he is not an esper, i.e., a human with supernatural abilities derived from scientific principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Espers complicate the narrative; their powers, based on scientific concepts, are stringently classified from Levels 1 to 5 (e.g., Accelerator, the strongest Level 5, who can alter &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vector_%28mathematics_and_physics%29&quot;&gt;vectors&lt;/a&gt;). They are the focal point of the &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; media installment, A Certain Scientific Railgun (とある科学の超電磁砲), which is a manga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;I&apos;m Not Like Other Franchises&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why discuss this franchise at all? A picture is worth a thousand words:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-zrh1-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.6435-9/66650262_2832607673478232_5292799112096251904_n.jpg?_nc_cat=104&amp;amp;ccb=1-7&amp;amp;_nc_sid=5f2048&amp;amp;_nc_ohc=xlJLehw46-QQ7kNvgEJONW7&amp;amp;_nc_ht=scontent-zrh1-1.xx&amp;amp;oh=00_AfDTqiW5hliHvm795f3jzKJCJa-bfyNxfeiU3nb16o9Qcg&amp;amp;oe=6653A7BC&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ToAruMajutsuNoIndexAndRailgunFanPage/posts/welcome-to-toaru-verse-timeline/2832609583478041/&quot;&gt;Toaru Universe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This illustrates the chronological order of the story; some fans meticulously follow this elaborate plan to navigate the main storyline&apos;s events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The franchise spans two main light novel series, two additional manga series, and three anime adaptations (Index, Railgun, and Accelerator). It also includes crossover events, video games dating back to the PSP era, and newly released manga adaptations of yet-to-be-adapted light novel content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This series serves as a case study in both incredible storytelling and problematic media management. We will explore both the benefits and the clear challenges of this system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Bad: Echo Chambers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Index, originally a light novel, was adapted into a manga by &lt;a href=&quot;https://toarumajutsunoindex.fandom.com/wiki/Kogino_Chuuya&quot;&gt;Kogino Chuuya&lt;/a&gt; and skipped the second and fourth novels. It was then adapted into an anime released in 2008 by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/J.C.Staff&quot;&gt;J.C.Staff&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its anime adaptation suffers from inconsistencies, poor pacing, and the dated early 2000s shonen trope, characterized by overt fanservice, harems, and a tsundere female companion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many traits present in the original light novel were either nonexistent or minimally emphasized. However, like an echo chamber, these were amplified with each adaptation, culminating in video games—based on the &lt;em&gt;adapted anime adapted from the manga adapted from the light novel&lt;/em&gt;—which essentially became fan-service farms, sometimes bordering on legality concerning some younger characters (yikes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This redundancy is a core issue with crossmedia. Recursive adaptations lead to a cumulative addition of elements, diluting the original essence into an unrecognizable mess that complicates the experience for fans, who often recommend a complex mix of different media to properly engage with the series: &quot;First read the novel, then this part was better in the manga, but Railgun&apos;s anime is well-adapted...&quot; and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Good: Comprehensive Worldbuilding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obsession with crossmedia isn&apos;t unwarranted; it not only enables the sale of a franchise across various platforms and diversifies revenue but also allows the franchise to experiment with new mediums and leverage their unique features to its advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s revisit the earlier diagram:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Ve0Gyu0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I&apos;ve translated this awesome series timeline (original in comments): r/toarumajutsunoindex&quot; /&gt;
Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/user/Skylinee77/&quot;&gt;Skylinee77&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This represents what is known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Worldbuilding&quot;&gt;comprehensive worldbuilding&lt;/a&gt;. While &lt;a href=&quot;https://toarumajutsunoindex.fandom.com/wiki/Kamijou_Touma&quot;&gt;Kamijou Touma&lt;/a&gt; is the de facto main character of Index, Railgun&apos;s protagonist &lt;a href=&quot;https://toarumajutsunoindex.fandom.com/wiki/Misaka_Mikoto&quot;&gt;Misaka Mikoto&lt;/a&gt; is almost universally more popular, and her anime adaptation is more critically acclaimed, underscoring the potential of this approach. &lt;a href=&quot;https://toarumajutsunoindex.fandom.com/wiki/Accelerator&quot;&gt;Accelerator&lt;/a&gt; is a character with a rich backstory that received its own series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Story arcs can be explored from various perspectives. Touma is not a main character per se but rather, like every other character, a witness to Academy City&apos;s storyline. This principle underscores Toaru&apos;s series philosophy: regardless of whether characters disappear or are completely forgotten, Academy City continues to exist and evolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having multiple mediums allows Academy City to feel &lt;em&gt;like a real place&lt;/em&gt;, where people lead full lives. It is a worldbuilding powerhouse, constructed on layers of lore that must be explored through various methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s analyze another diagram:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.baka-tsuki.org/project/thumb.php?f=A_Certain_Unified_Calendar.png&amp;amp;width=900&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Credit : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.baka-tsuki.org/project/index.php?title=Index_Calendar&quot;&gt;Baka-Tsuki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Events here are static; &lt;em&gt;they do not change regardless of the medium&lt;/em&gt;. May-21 marks the point at which the current story halted, as depicted. Some days are shared by multiple mediums (represented by the keys); these are entire arcs that are either partially reexplored or completely redone from another perspective. The most prominent example is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://toarumajutsunoindex.fandom.com/wiki/Sisters_Arc&quot;&gt;Sisters Arc&lt;/a&gt;, which appears in the Light Novels, the Index and Railgun Mangas, as well as the Index, Railgun, and Accelerator anime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This depth is a significant reason this arc is so well-regarded, and it exemplifies why many fans are prepared to follow such a complex schedule religiously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Paradox Itself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paradox of the Toaru franchise, and crossmedia ventures in general, lies in the tension between expanding a universe and maintaining its core essence. On one hand, crossmedia allows for a richer exploration of the world and characters, providing multiple angles and deeper layers to the story. On the other hand, it risks diluting the original themes and alienating parts of the audience who may prefer the narrative and stylistic coherence of the original medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary challenge with crossmedia adaptations is that each medium brings its own set of storytelling tools and limitations. What works in a novel—internal monologues, detailed world-building, complex backstories—might not translate well to a video game or a TV series, where visual and interactive elements take precedence. This shift can fundamentally alter the story&apos;s presentation and impact, leading to a product that feels disconnected from the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With each new adaptation, there&apos;s a risk of overextending the franchise. The desire to reach new audiences and markets can lead to forced adaptations that compromise on quality. Each additional layer might add complexity, but it can also introduce contradictions and inconsistencies that confuse both new viewers and long-time fans. This overextension can dilute the brand&apos;s identity, making it hard for any single adaptation to stand out as definitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Toaru franchise exemplifies the crossmedia paradox: &lt;em&gt;the balance between expanding a story across different platforms and maintaining the integrity of its original narrative.&lt;/em&gt; While it offers unique opportunities for world-building and character development, it also faces the pitfalls of inconsistency, audience fragmentation, and potential quality compromise. This balancing act is the crux of the crossmedia challenge—pushing the boundaries of storytelling while respecting the essence that attracted fans in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, whether crossmedia is a boon or a bane to a franchise depends on how carefully and thoughtfully the adaptations are managed. It requires a harmonious integration of all forms of media to enrich the original work without overshadowing it, a feat easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Toaru&apos;s journey through the labyrinth of crossmedia adaptation provides both a blueprint and a cautionary tale. It illustrates the potential for expansive storytelling and deep, immersive world-building, as well as the risks of losing the narrative&apos;s heart and soul amidst the drive to explore every possible avenue. As we look to the future of entertainment, the lessons from Toaru could guide new crossmedia endeavors to strike a better balance between innovation and integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To wrap this all up, here is the first opening of the anime adaptation of Railgun cuz this s***&apos;s a bop:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;YouTube id=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=amMvCBcInXs&amp;amp;ab_channel=%F0%9D%99%B7%F0%9D%9A%8A%F0%9D%9A%98-%F0%9D%9A%86%F0%9D%9A%8E%F0%9D%9A%92&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Anime Review</category><category>Toaru</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>My ranking of Jojo parts, and why (mild spoilers).</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/jojo_ranking/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/jojo_ranking/</guid><description>Yes, I am serious, this is my blog and I can write whatever I want.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;import { YouTube } from &quot;astro-embed&quot;;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;My ranking of Jojo parts, and why.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a fan of Jojo for a long time, and I have seen all the parts. I know that everyone has their own opinions on which part is the best, but I wanted to share my ranking of the parts and why I think they are the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be ranking the parts from my least favorite to my favorite, so let&apos;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. Phantom Blood&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Phantom Blood is not a bad part by any means, And I mean it. There is a lot to love about Jonathan&apos;s part and I&apos;m part of the people that think introductory parts don&apos;t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to be entertaining as long as they bring important input to the lore which is exactly what Phantom Blood does. I mean heck, I love Clannad, even with the infamously hard to get into first season, because you are rewarded for it with After Story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the same situation: I love the Dio of Phantom Blood, Hamon is a cool mechanic that will be the key of Battle Tendency, and without this part, the logic behind &lt;em&gt;fate&lt;/em&gt; in Jojo wouldn&apos;t be understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wallpapers.com/images/hd/phantom-blood-1920-x-1080-wallpaper-uy1zu644msdgzqcx.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. Battle Tendency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oooh, Battle Tendency&apos;s a tough one.
Hated by some, loved by others, to me Battle Tendency is where Araki truly started understanding what he wanted to do with Jojo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamon is an interesting technique, it puts into play the idea of the importance of the environnement during battles,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph is an amazing protagonist too, hotheaded, always getting away with whatever he wants, the anime adaptation truly did justice to these early parts, and the music ?
I don&apos;t have to say anything except:
&amp;lt;YouTube id=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lRrOLTHu-ew&amp;amp;ab_channel=AnimeOST&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Golden Wind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Golden Wind is a part that I have mixed feelings about. On one hand, I love the characters and the setting, but on the other hand, I feel like the story is a bit lacking compared to the other parts. I think that the main villain, Diavolo, is lacking in comparison to other villains like Dio and Kira,
thankfully his alter ego Doppio is a great character that makes up for it -- I mean the guy talks to Diavolo through a make-shift phone, how cool is that ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main cast, and this arc&apos;s jobros are the best for sure. Mista, Abbacchio and Narancia are all great characters though they aren&apos;t as incredibly memorable as Bucciarati !
Fugo... kinda just exists, but he&apos;s cool too.
I mean, Bucciarati has Sticky Fingers, and he&apos;s the one that made me realize that stands can be more than just a power, they can be a part of the character&apos;s personality -- probably my favorite character in all jojo too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s hard to talk about Golden Wind without talking about the character designs, which are some of the best in the series.
From Giorno&apos;s hair, to the outfits of the main cast, everything is so well designed and memorable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real issue with Golden Wind is both the ending (and its pacing), Giorno&apos;s lack of development, and the fact that the main villain is just not as interesting as the other villains in the series.
He&apos;s obviously, like other Jojos, someone with a lot of heart and determination, but he&apos;s not as interesting as the other Jojos in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://wallpapercave.com/wp/wp4640795.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Stardust Crusaders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stardust Crusaders is probably the part most people think of when they think of Jojo, and for good reason, since it both introduced stands and Jotaro.
Need I say what I think of Jotaro ? He&apos;s probably the most iconic of all Jojos, beyond the obvious badassery, he has a lot of depth, and his relationship with his grandfather is one of the best in the series.
This part also has some of the best fights in the series, with memorable stand users like D&apos;Arby, Vanilla Ice, and of course, Dio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main issue with Stardust Crusaders is that it&apos;s a bit too long, and some of the fights can feel a bit repetitive, it introduced the &quot;stand of the week&quot; formula that would be used in later parts, but it&apos;s not as well executed as in Diamond is Unbreakable.
Lore-wise however, it is an essential part of the series, and it&apos;s a must-watch for any Jojo fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/ZMBMQ8W/52395775-p0-master1200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
Credit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pixiv.net/en/users/1804221&quot;&gt;空出 羽衣&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I wouldn&apos;t watch the anime adaptation, in fact that&apos;s not how I watched it myself.
Here&apos;s what I did instead:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I read the manga until the end of the D&apos;Arby fight, then I watched the OVA, and then I watched the anime adaptation.
I think that&apos;s the best way to experience Stardust Crusaders, since the OVA has a different tone than the anime adaptation, and it&apos;s a nice change of pace.
Plus, the OVA has some great animation, and it&apos;s a nice way to see the characters in a different light, you guys have to see Abdul&apos;s charadesign in the OVA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;YouTube id=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sYBzjXY-tg0&amp;amp;ab_channel=LRAMV25&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Steel Ball Run&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can already hear the fans screaming at me for putting Steel Ball Run so low on the list, but hear me out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, the pacing is a bit slow, and it takes a while for the story to get going especially the first 10 chapters, but once it does, it&apos;s amazing.
It was very tough for me not to be bored to death during the horse back riding sections, but the characters and the story are so well written that it&apos;s worth it.
That&apos;s why it so &lt;em&gt;high&lt;/em&gt; in fact, because if it wasn&apos;t for the ending and the great characters that happened after the reset, I wouldn&apos;t have even taken the time to finish it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;d rather not spoil much of Steel Ball Run because many people are anime-onlys, but I will say that the ending is one of the best in the series, and it&apos;s worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Diamond is Unbreakable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diamond is Unbreakable is probably the most unique part of Jojo, and that&apos;s why I love it so much.
The best way I would describe it is : A slice of life with stands ; what an incredible forumula, right ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, the &quot;Adventure&quot; part of Jojo&apos;s Bizarre Adventure is just different enough to make it stand out from the other parts, and it&apos;s a nice change of pace from the more serious parts like Stardust Crusaders and Golden Wind.
It&apos;s just plain old fun, and Josuke is one my favorite Jojos, he&apos;s just so cool and laid back, and his relationship with his friends is one of the best in the series.
You can tell that Araki had a lot of fun writing this part, and it really shows in the characters and the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The artstyle is my favorite in the series, and those openings, my God not a single one misses,
But of course, Great Days with that chorus is insane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;YouTube id=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ATYTLw-Nl0s&amp;amp;ab_channel=Neobrane&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only that, but Kira is one of the best villains in the series,
What makes him so interesting is how truly normal he is, just like the town of Morioh itelf, Kira is a calm and collected man, careful of every move he makes and he genuinely believes that all he wants is a quiet life.
He&apos;s a great contrast to the more over-the-top villains like Dio and Diavolo, and it&apos;s refreshing to see a villain who is so different from the others in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a villan that wants the exact opposite of taking over the world in some way is incredibly refreshing, and it makes Kira &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; de facto best villain for most people, me included.
And how can I not talk about this part&apos;s jobros ? Rohan, Okuyasu, Koichi, and Jotaro are all great characters, and they all have their own unique personalities and abilities that make them stand out from the other jobros in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This part has the most powerfuls stands such as Killer Queen, Crazy Diamond, Heaven&apos;s Door, and Star Platinum, and the fights are some of the best in the series.
I guess where Diamond is Unbreakable really gets it is the &lt;em&gt;ambiance&lt;/em&gt;, that&apos;s something a lot of people forget about. Having a well-paced anime is cool and all, but if the ambiance, the feeling of the part isn&apos;t there, then it&apos;s not a good adaptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun and Lighthearted, Addictive and Thrilling, Diamond is Unbreakable is a must-watch for any Jojo fan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static1.cbrimages.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/diamond-is-unbreakable-promo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Stone Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stone Ocean is my favorite part of Jojo,
Yes, you&apos;ve read that right, Stone Ocean is my favorite part of Jojo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, while prisons are a common setting in Jojo, they&apos;re often used as tools to introduce the main characters to the story, and then they&apos;re quickly abandoned.
Stone Ocean is different, it&apos;s set in a prison, and it&apos;s a major part of the story, and it&apos;s a great setting for the story to take place in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.distractify.com/brand-img/FG78rq1JK/0x0/stone-ocean-anime-prison-1638909626901.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prisons provide an interesting environnement where violence is a part of everyday life, and it&apos;s a great place for the characters to develop and grow, we saw that with Jolyne, who started off as a rebellious teenager, and then she grew into a strong and independent woman.
That&apos;s not to say she wasn&apos;t introduced as such, in fact one of the more interesting scenes is when she&apos;s first arrested, and talks about her probably being seen by the police officer doing... things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean most series wouldn&apos;t even dare get anywhere near such a subject, but Jolyne is written so incredibly well, that it&apos;s not even a problem.
I admit this is where I am very biased, having well written strong female characters is so rare in media that I can&apos;t help but love Jolyne.
Her stand is interesting too, while it&apos;s definitely no where near my favorite, I like how creative you can get with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/yWDMkkB/Love-Liner-x-JOJO-Stone-Ocean-Jolyne.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I feel like most people disliked Stone Ocean because of the way Netflix partitioned the series, and I can&apos;t blame them, it&apos;s a terrible way to watch the series.
I happen to have read it first, then watched the anime all in one go, and honestly that way it&apos;s a great experience.
The pacing is perfect, the animation is great, and the voice acting is top-notch, and while I admit this part has the weakest Jobros, they&apos;re still great characters, and they all have their own unique personalities and abilities that make them stand out from the other jobros in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where this part really gets the price for the best part however is with its villain.
Pucci isn&apos;t one of the, but &lt;em&gt;THE&lt;/em&gt; best villain in the series, having someone with such a supposed holy role within the prison be the villain is interesting, pucci&apos;s push for evolution, his belief in a concept as important in the series as fate make him an interesting character to study.
In fact, I think that Pucci is the most interesting villain in the series, and his relationship with Jolyne is one of the best in the series:
See, gravitation is often used in this part, it comes from a concept that was pushed even further in Diamond is Unbreakable where we learn that Stand users are drawn to each other,
But in Stone Ocean, it&apos;s pushed even further, and it&apos;s a great way to show how the characters are connected to each other, and how they&apos;re all part of the same story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/dW0h5PC/Eu-Vgb-IFXMAI8-BE6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the stands in this part are truly something else,
From Stone Free, to Weather Report, to Made in Heaven, the stands in this part are some of the most creative ones in the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weather Report controls the weather completely using subliminal messaging ?
White Snake can steal memories and stands ?
C-Moon can reverse gravity &lt;em&gt;AROUND THE USER&lt;/em&gt; ??
Made in Heaven is a stand that can accelerate time to the point where the universe resets itself ???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images-wixmp-ed30a86b8c4ca887773594c2.wixmp.com/f/5851f423-3ac3-4eef-88d5-2be0fc69382b/dfje364-dc59be51-e777-44fd-8ebf-02163962e206.png/v1/fill/w_688,h_1161,q_70,strp/jojo_enrico_pucci_s_stands_by_mdwyer5_dfje364-pre.jpg?token=eyJ0eXAiOiJKV1QiLCJhbGciOiJIUzI1NiJ9.eyJzdWIiOiJ1cm46YXBwOjdlMGQxODg5ODIyNjQzNzNhNWYwZDQxNWVhMGQyNmUwIiwiaXNzIjoidXJuOmFwcDo3ZTBkMTg4OTgyMjY0MzczYTVmMGQ0MTVlYTBkMjZlMCIsIm9iaiI6W1t7ImhlaWdodCI6Ijw9MjE2MCIsInBhdGgiOiJcL2ZcLzU4NTFmNDIzLTNhYzMtNGVlZi04OGQ1LTJiZTBmYzY5MzgyYlwvZGZqZTM2NC1kYzU5YmU1MS1lNzc3LTQ0ZmQtOGViZi0wMjE2Mzk2MmUyMDYucG5nIiwid2lkdGgiOiI8PTEyODAifV1dLCJhdWQiOlsidXJuOnNlcnZpY2U6aW1hZ2Uub3BlcmF0aW9ucyJdfQ.tiSHpg83ms_jXUJGlvMzkvOotHTLgcg0YDjblvk9gSg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emporio&apos;s relationship with Jolyne is one of the most endearing ones too,
FF&apos;s sacrifice is one of the most heartbreaking moments in the series,
And the storyline about Pucci and Weather Report&apos;s past is mindblowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stone Ocean is a must-watch for any Jojo fan, and is so far for me the most well written.
Many do the mistake of skipping it to get to Steel Ball Run, but I think there isn&apos;t a bigger mistake that could be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, Stone Ocean&apos;s last opening is the best in the series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;YouTube id=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DOzJqyi178A&amp;amp;ab_channel=Neobrane&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so is its last ending, which honesly broke my heart, mostly because of how much I pity Emporio,
While I was angry in the beginning seeing the universe getting reset, I understand it was a necessity, you probably can&apos;t go any further than that, and series already got scary close to modern day too, they can&apos;t place Jojo in the future without it being a mess.
Rounding (heh) everything up with Roundabout was a great choice, nice callback to the first part, and a great way to end the series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;YouTube id=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L1sUOQPjBqg&amp;amp;ab_channel=Neobrane&quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Anime Review</category><category>Jojo</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>My Steepster reviews !</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/my-steepster-reviews-/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/my-steepster-reviews-/</guid><description>I have been writing reviews on Steepster for a while now, and I thought it would be a good idea to share them here as well. I will be posting them in batches, so stay tuned !</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been writing reviews on &lt;a href=&quot;https://steepster.com/Yaroster&quot;&gt;Steepster&lt;/a&gt; for a while now, and I thought it would be a good idea to share them here as well. I will be posting them in batches, so stay tuned !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you will enjoy reading them as much as I enjoyed writing them !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !
Yaroster&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Announcement</category><category>Tea Review</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>Review of Fleur de Sureau et Pêche Bio by Palais des Thés</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-fleur-de-sureau-et-peche-bio-by-palais-des-thes/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-fleur-de-sureau-et-peche-bio-by-palais-des-thes/</guid><description>Review of Fleur de Sureau et Pêche Bio by Palais des Thés</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Review of Fleur de Sureau et Pêche Bio by Palais des Thés&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently tried Fleur de Sureau et Pêche Bio, a tea blend from Palais des Thés. Here&apos;s my detailed review of the experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this tea so much! The peach is clear, and yet it does not overpower the elderflower, which is also very noticeable. It&apos;s a perfect balance of flavors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt; 95°C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 min (initial steep), followed by consecutive 30s/1min steeps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tea Amount:&lt;/strong&gt; 2.5 g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; A bit less than 80 mL (in my gaiwan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://shop.sinas.online/media/image/cd/a5/32/21870_600x600@2x.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tasting Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went for an initial steep at 95°C for 2 minutes, followed by consecutive 30-second/1-minute steeps. The point here was to see how concentrated the taste could be, and it was worth it. The tea has a very subtle yet distinctive taste, making it a perfect morning brew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Flavor Profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flavors are clear, with the elderflower and peach both shining through without overpowering each other. It&apos;s a delightful blend that offers a refreshing start to the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flavors: Clear, Elderflower, Peach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation: Highly recommended for its perfect balance of flavors and refreshing taste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;85/100&lt;/h1&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Tea Review</category><category>Palais des Thés</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>Review of Grand Yunnan Impérial by Palais des Thés</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-grand-yunnan-imperial-by-palais-des-thes/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-grand-yunnan-imperial-by-palais-des-thes/</guid><description>Review of Grand Yunnan Impérial by Palais des Thés</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Review of Grand Yunnan Impérial by Palais des Thés&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://us.palaisdesthes.com/media/catalog/product/cache/50708da259540eeb20337bcdb367a3c9/2/2/220-34816-wmr7f3mou6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grand Yunnan Impérial&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently tried Grand Yunnan Impérial, a black tea from Palais des Thés. Here&apos;s my detailed review of the experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt; 205°F / 96°C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0 min, 15 sec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tea Amount:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 oz / 100 ml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a disappointing initial attempt with a steep time of 45 seconds resulting in strong bitterness, I decided to switch to Gong Fu style brewing to explore the tea&apos;s potential further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;First Infusion (10s)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the first infusion, I steeped the tea for about 10 seconds, aiming to quickly extract the flavor without letting it become bitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Second Infusion (15s)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second infusion was very relaxing, with the expected bitterness for a black tea. However, it didn&apos;t exhibit any outstanding characteristics beyond being a standard Yunnan black tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Third Infusion (10s)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third infusion revealed the tea&apos;s potential as the bitterness subsided, leaving a lighter and more enjoyable experience. This infusion was particularly praised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Fourth Infusion (25s)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the fourth infusion, the bitterness became more pronounced, but no significant difference was noted compared to the third infusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overall Impression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, Grand Yunnan Impérial proved to be a non-exceptional yet pleasant black tea. It exhibited slightly less bitterness than expected, making it suitable for casual consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation: Would recommend for casual consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;67/100&lt;/h1&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Tea Review</category><category>Palais des Thés</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>Review of Pu Erh Lin Cang BIO by Palais des Thés</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-pu-erh-lin-cang-bio-by-palais-des-thes/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-pu-erh-lin-cang-bio-by-palais-des-thes/</guid><description>Review of Pu Erh Lin Cang BIO by Palais des Thés</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Review of Pu Erh Lin Cang BIO by Palais des Thés&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently tried Pu Erh Lin Cang BIO, a tea from Palais des Thés. Here&apos;s my detailed review of the experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first pu&apos;er tea, and maybe my last dark pu&apos;er for a while. I&apos;m still new to tea, and this one is a bit challenging for me. While the earthiness wasn’t too strong and I could distinctly sense the typical pu&apos;er aroma, I admit it’s just too out there for me. However, it&apos;s an overall good tea that needs to be tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt; 205°F / 96°C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steeping Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0 min, 30 sec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tea Amount:&lt;/strong&gt; 4 g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 oz / 100 mL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://0db7181a.flyingcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/1878_Puerh_Bio-PhotoRoom.png-PhotoRoom.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tasting Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I brewed it with 30-second steeps, using 4g of tea per 100mL of water. The experience was okay, but it didn&apos;t quite match my taste preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Flavor Profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tea has a strong earthy flavor and a viscous texture, which are typical characteristics of pu&apos;er tea. While some may enjoy these qualities, I found them to be too intense for my liking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flavors: Earthy, Viscous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation: Recommended for those who enjoy bold, earthy flavors in their tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;60/100&lt;/h1&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Tea Review</category><category>Palais des Thés</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>Review of Sencha Ariake by Palais des Thés</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-sencha-ariake-by-palais-des-thes/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-sencha-ariake-by-palais-des-thes/</guid><description>Review of Sencha Ariake by Palais des Thés</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Review of Sencha Ariake by Palais des Thés&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently tried Sencha Ariake, a green tea from Palais des Thés. Here&apos;s my detailed review of the experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt; 160°F / 71°C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 min, 0 sec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tea Amount:&lt;/strong&gt; 5 g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 oz / 100 ml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some pretty negative apprehensions when I was about to try this tea,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As many others, I find most Japanese teas to be too herbal, vegetably even; having that typical astringency that you find in especially cheap ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Matchas and Senchas, it’s not uncommon to find herbalness mixed with a strong and direct bitterness that rules over every other subtleties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this wasn’t one of those cases, in fact it is one of the only senchas I was able to drink gong fu style — albeit with some consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sencha&apos;s particularity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why Sencha isn’t really compatible with gong fu style, its finely cut needle-like leaves are hard to block and Sencha is usually infused for long periods of time, a kyusu thusly being the more logical vessel to be used and more generally, the tea itself doesn’t benefit much from a tea “cleaning” per se since the leaves are already broken, so I’m gonna drink that 1st steep anyways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.palaisdesthes.com/media/catalog/product/cache/50708da259540eeb20337bcdb367a3c9/3/0/302-35746-ptx0icd86w.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that in mind, I tried a different method. First, I would infuse for 2 minutes at 70C, then I would make two more 20s steeps, any more would be too bitter.
Here’s how it went:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;First Steep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The herbal notes were prominent in the first steep, with minimal bitterness. However, allowing the tea to cool slightly increased its bitterness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Second Steep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bitterness overwhelmed the second steep, rendering it almost undrinkable. The vegetable-like taste remained present but overshadowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Third Steep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the third steep, the herbal notes had disappeared entirely, leaving behind a strong bitterness akin to drinking ear wax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overall Impression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, although it may seem as if I hated this tea, this is truly one of the most suprising ones I’ve tried so far. The first thing that came to my mind when I drank that first steep was “fresh”, it was just fresh and very vegetably, like cucumber water. Just for that first steep, and the shock that it caused, this tea deserves more recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flavors: Cucumber, Fresh, Herbal, Vegetables&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation: An intriguing tea worth trying for its surprising flavors, particularly in the first steep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;75/100&lt;/h1&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Tea Review</category><category>Palais des Thés</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>Review of Thé des Moines by Palais des Thés</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-the-des-moines-by-palais-des-thes/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-the-des-moines-by-palais-des-thes/</guid><description>Review of Thé des Moines by Palais des Thés</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt; 175°F / 79°C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 min, 0 sec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tea Amount:&lt;/strong&gt; 4 g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 oz / 100 ml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this tasting, I experimented with a gaiwan and utilized a somewhat unconventional brewing method: 80°C water temperature, 4g of tea per 100ml of water, steeped for 3 minutes for the initial steep, followed by constant 10-second steeps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lapothicaire.ca/cdn/shop/products/IMG_8990_1024x1024.jpg?v=1511483699&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Second Steep&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second steep revealed plenty of jasmine notes upfront, accompanied by a strong clove-like taste and some floral notes. Unfortunately, the experience was marred by an incredibly bitter aftertaste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Third, Fourth, and Subsequent Steeps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continued steeping, the floral notes became more pronounced, with the jasmine dominating completely and leaving no room for any other aroma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overall Impression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the bitterness in the second steep, I found the blend to be quite enjoyable overall. The complexity of flavors, particularly in the second steep, was remarkable and not something encountered in most teas. While the unconventional brewing method may have contributed to the bitterness, I believe that proper gongfu style brewing could yield better results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation: Recommended for its complexity and pleasant flavors, especially when brewed with care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;70/100&lt;/h1&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Tea Review</category><category>Palais des Thés</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>Review of Thé du Hammam by Palais des Thés</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-th%C3%A9-du-hammam-by-palais-des-thesds/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/review-of-th%C3%A9-du-hammam-by-palais-des-thesds/</guid><description>Review of Thé du Hammam by Palais des Thés</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;Review of Thé du Hammam by Palais des Thés&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently tried Thé du Hammam, a tea blend from Palais des Thés. Here&apos;s my detailed review of the experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt; 170°F / 76°C&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 min, 15 sec&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tea Amount:&lt;/strong&gt; 2 g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 oz / 100 ml&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://us.palaisdesthes.com/media/catalog/product/cache/50708da259540eeb20337bcdb367a3c9/8/6/861-42158-rh8x3mmwnv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thé du Hammam was quite a shocker for me. My experience doesn’t seem to fit what I expected. It’s sweet and subtle, both traits that are important for a tea that describes itself as inspired by oriental hammam&apos;s scents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flavor Profile&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my issue, out of the four elements of the tea, only two seem to be noticeable, with one overpowering the other: the green date (notable in the aftertaste) and the rose (subtle at the front of the taste). The green date is something I never expected in a tea, providing a very refreshing form of sweetness, while the rose adds a nice touch for that Hammam-like taste. However, I didn&apos;t detect any signs of orange flower water or red fruits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Overall Impression&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a recurring theme in Palais des Thés flavored teas; they tend to be too perfumy, lacking much-needed substance. While some of their recipes hit the mark, this one falls short in delivering a well-balanced flavor profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tasting Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have tried this tea twice, once in a gaiwan with 30-second steeps at 75°C and 2.5g/100ml, and once in a teapot with 6g/300ml, 75°C, steeped for 3 minutes. Unfortunately, both experiences have been disappointing so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sad because I deeply wanted to love this tea, but for Palais des Thés teas, I think I’ll just stick to their pure teas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flavors: Dates, Rose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation: Not recommended due to its lack of balance and underwhelming flavor profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;33/100&lt;/h1&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Tea Review</category><category>Palais des Thés</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>Welcome to the skoomaDen !</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/welcome-to-the-skoomaden-/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/welcome-to-the-skoomaden-/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m Yaroster, owner of the hand behind the Den !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we&apos;ll talk about everything from tea to coding, from games to books, from music to movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you&apos;ll enjoy your stay here, and that you&apos;ll find something that will make you smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The den is always open to whomever wishes, so don&apos;t hesitate to come in and say hi !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you soon !&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Annoucements</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item><item><title>What&apos;s in my cupboard, April 2024</title><link>https://skoomaden.me/posts/whats-in-my-cupboard-april-2024/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://skoomaden.me/posts/whats-in-my-cupboard-april-2024/</guid><description>An overview of the teas I drank in April 2024 !</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h1&gt;What&apos;s in my cupboard, April 2024&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a month!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to try a lot of new teas, and I&apos;m excited to share my thoughts with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month, I drank exclusively Palais des Thés teas, and I was not disappointed.
It was all drank in my new Gaiwan !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.ibb.co/WnjhX2B/Whats-App-Image-2024-04-25-at-17-36-54-caadef59.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The teas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thé du Hammam:
A fruity blend which evokes the fragrances used to perfume the hammam: roses, green dates, red fruit and orange flower water. A tea I&apos;ve been trying to get my hands on for a while !
&lt;img src=&quot;https://us.palaisdesthes.com/media/catalog/product/cache/50708da259540eeb20337bcdb367a3c9/8/6/861-42158-rh8x3mmwnv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thé des Moines:
A Flowery tea blend inspired by a secret Tibetan recipe.
An ancient legend tells of how the Tibetan monks would prepare this blend of tea, plants and flowers in the greatest of secrecy. After several days of soaking, the leaves were carefully plucked out and put to one side.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://lachocolatiere.ch/811-product_detail/the-des-moines-sachet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thé des Lords:
A wonderful Earl Grey with a pronounced bergamot flavor, enhanced with safflower petals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lachocolatiere.ch/828-product_detail/the-des-lords-vrac.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grand Yunnan Impérial:
The subtle flavor of this flowery, mild tea is known as the “Mocha of teas” or “Surgeon’s tea”, as it has the power to revive without over-stimulating the nerves. A splendid leaf with plenty of golden buds.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://us.palaisdesthes.com/media/catalog/product/cache/50708da259540eeb20337bcdb367a3c9/2/2/220-34816-wmr7f3mou6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grand Jasmin Mao Feng:
A very rare jasmine tea composed almost entirely of tips. This tea disappeared for a long time before the Fujian province began producing it again in very small quantities.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://us.palaisdesthes.com/media/catalog/product/cache/50708da259540eeb20337bcdb367a3c9/2/4/249-35707-bd3y9mplxo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pu Erh Li Cang BIO:
A simple yet potent young Pu&apos;erh, great tea to start the notoriously strong and earty tea type.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://0db7181a.flyingcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/1878_Puerh_Bio-PhotoRoom.png-PhotoRoom.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bai Mu Dan:
Chinese for &quot;White peony&quot;, it is a very fine tea, made up of all sorts of leaves in their natural state: silvery buds, Souchong leaves, first and second leaves and stems.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.palaisdesthes.com/media/catalog/product/cache/50708da259540eeb20337bcdb367a3c9/1/9/1940.jpg.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sencha Ariake:
Produced in the province of Kyushu, Sencha Ariake is the mildest of the great Sencha teas. A lot of apprehension for that one, the vegetable-ness of Japanese teas always challenged me.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.palaisdesthes.com/media/catalog/product/cache/50708da259540eeb20337bcdb367a3c9/3/0/302-35746-ptx0icd86w.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fleur de Sureau et Pêche Bio:
A very humble peach flavored elderflower tea, smells very alcohol-y. Cannot wait to try this one out.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://shop.sinas.online/media/image/cd/a5/32/21870_600x600@2x.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reviews&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reviews are coming soon for these teas ! I cannot wait to talk about how that went !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you guys soon !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers !
Yaroster.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded><category>Cupboard</category><author>yaroster&apos;s</author></item></channel></rss>